Guide to the Ronald Spector papers, 1968-2019 MS2396
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ronald Spector papers
1968-2014
1990-2014
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Spector, Ronald H., 1943-
MS2396
9.5 Linear Feet
This collection contains formal and informal correspondence, syllabi, assignments, quizzes/exams, lecture notes, student records, professorship paperwork, resumes, promotional information, research scans and notes, unpublished drafts, conference materials, antique collecting receipts, and copies of published work. The materials date from 1968-2014, with the bulk of the materials dated from 1990-2014. The records document historian Ronald Spector's teaching and writing career, and also include other materials about history projects with which he was involved.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research but contains some restricted material related to students and employees at George Washington University. Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Researchers interested in boxes from Series 1, 2 and 3 should contact Special Collections staff to request materials. SCRC staff may need to review folders before researchers can access them.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ronald Spector, 2019 (Accession 2019.052)
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Correspondence, Course Materials, Professional Acitivity
Biographical / Historical
Ronald Spector (1943-) taught history at George Washington University from 1990-2019. His career began in the United States Marine Corps, where he served in the Vietnam War. He received a bachelor's degree from Johns Hopkins University and Ph.D. from Yale University. In addition to teaching, he has published five books and made several contributions to scholarly journals. He has received the Samuel Eliot Morison Prize for his contributions to military history, and his book Eagle Against the Sun: The American War with Japan won the Theodore and Franklin D. Roosevelt Prize in Naval History in 1986. Some of his other major publications include After Tet: The Bloodiest Year in Vietnam (1993) and In the Ruins of Empire: The Japanese Surrender and the Battle for Postwar Asia (2007)."
Scope and Contents
This collection contains formal and informal correspondence, syllabi, assignments, quizzes/exams, lecture notes, student records, professorship paperwork, resumes, promotional information, research scans and notes, unpublished drafts, conference materials, antique collecting receipts, and copies of published work. The materials date from 1968-2019, with the bulk of the materials dated from 1990-2014. The records document historian Ronald Spector's teaching and writing career, and also include other materials about history projects with which he was involved.
Asia; Books; Faculty; Historians; History; Publishers and publishing -- United States; World War, 1939-1945; Spector, Ronald H., 1943-
- Correspondence, 1971-2005; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Series is organized alphabetically by last name of other party in correspondence and then chronologically by year. For example, Folder 1: "A Correspondence 1971" and Folder 2: "A Correspondence 1972"
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include letters and emails sent by and from Ronald Spector regarding classes, book and article publications, historical research projects, museum exhibitions, travel, and events. The material dates from 1971-2005.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Some of the folders in this series contain student records and other confidential personal information. Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Researchers interested in boxes from Series 1 should contact Special Collections staff before requesting materials. SCRC staff may need to review folders before researchers can access them.
  - A Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Correspondence, 1984-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - A Correspondence, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - A Correspondence #2 of 2, 1990-1994; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - A Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - A Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - A Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - A Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - A Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - A Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - A Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - A Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - B Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B Correspondence, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - B Correspondence #2 of 2, 1990-1994; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - B Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - B Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - B Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - B Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - B Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - B Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - B Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - B Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - B Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - B Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - C Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C Correspondence #2 of 3, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - C Correspondence #3 of 3, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - C Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - C Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - C Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - C Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - C Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - C Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - C Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - C Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - C Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - C Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - C Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - D Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D Correspondence, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - D Correspondence #2 of 2, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - D Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - D Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - D Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - D Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - D Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - D Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - D Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - D Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - D Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - D Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - E Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - E Correspondence, 1984-1994; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - E Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - E Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - E Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - E Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - E Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - E Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - E Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - E Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - E Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - E Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - F Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F Correspondence, 1985-1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - F Correspondence #2 of 2, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - F Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - F Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - F Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - F Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - F Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - F Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - F Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - F Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - F Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - F Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - F Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - G Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - G Correspondence, 1982-1994; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - G Correspondence, 1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - G Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - G Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - G Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - G Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - G Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - G Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - G Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - G Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - G Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - G Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Rules and Procedures, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - H Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - H Correspondence, 1984-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - H Correspondence, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - H Correspondence, 1995; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - H Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - H Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - H Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - H Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - H Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - H Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - H Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - H Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - H Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - I Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - I Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - I Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - I Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - I Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - I Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - I Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - I Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - I Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - I Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - I Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - J Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - J Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - J Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - J Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - J Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - J Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - J Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - J Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - J Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - J Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - J Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - J Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - K Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - K Correspondece #2 of 2, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - K Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - K Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - K Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - K Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - K Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - K Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - K Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - K Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - K Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - K Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - K Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - L Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - L Correspondence, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - L Correspondence #2 of 2, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - L Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - L Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - L Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - L Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - L Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - L Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - L Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - L Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - L Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - L Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - L Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - M Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - M Corresondence, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - M Correspondence #2 of 3, 1988-1991; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - M Correspondence #3 of 3, 1992; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - M Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - M Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - M Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - M Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - M Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - M Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - M Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - M Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - M Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - M Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - M Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - N Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - N Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - N Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - N Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - N Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - N Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - N Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - N Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - N Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - N Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - N Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - N Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - N Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - O Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - O Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - O Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - O Correspondence, 1997; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - O Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - O Correspondence, 1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - O Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - O Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - O Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - O Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - O Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - O Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - P Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - P Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - P Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - P Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - P Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - P Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - P Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - PQ Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - PQ Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - PQ Correspondence, 1971-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - PQ Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - PQ Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Q Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Q Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Q Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Q Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Q Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - R Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - R Correspondence, 1985-1991; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - R Correspondence, 1992; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - R Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - R Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - R Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - R Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - R Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - R Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - R Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - R Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - R Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - S Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - S Correspondence #1 of 2, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - S Correspondence #1 of 2, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - S Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - S Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - S Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - S Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - S Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - S Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - S Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - S Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - S Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Surveys, undated; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - T Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - T Correspondence, 1985-1989; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - T Correspondence #2 of 2, 1990; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - T Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - T Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - T Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - T Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - T Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - T Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - T Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - T Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - U Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - U Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - U Correspondence, 1995; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - U Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - U Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - U Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - U Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - U Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - UV Correspondence, 1997-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - V Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - V Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - V Correspondence, 1995-1996; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - V Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - V Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - V Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - V Correspondence, 2002; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - V Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - V Correspondence, 2004-2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - W Correspondence, 1971-1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - W Correspondence, 1985; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - W Correspondence, 1996-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - W Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - W Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - W Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - W Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - W Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - W Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 1984; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 1995; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 1996-1998; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 1999; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 2000; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 2003; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - XYZ Correspondence, 2005; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - X Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - X Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Y Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Y Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Z Correspondence, 2001; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Z Correspondence, 2004; MS2396 Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 40)
- Course Materials, 1989-2013; undated; Series 2
  Series is organized alphabetically by folder title. If there are multiple folders for a single course, they are organized chronologically.
  Materials in this series include syllabi, assignments, quizzes/exams, lecture notes, and student records from courses taught by Ronald Spector. The majority of these course materials pertain to George Washington University, but there also are some records from other institutions at which he taught. The materials date from 1989-2013.
  Some of the folders in this series contain student records and other confidential personal information. Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Researchers interested in boxes from Series 2 should contact Special Collections staff before requesting materials. SCRC staff may need to review folders before researchers can access them.
  - Elective, undated; MS2396 Series 2 (Box 16, Folder 1)